In this video, we will develop an algorithm for
在本视频中，我们将为
a particular pattern of blue and red squares on a grid.
网格上蓝色和红色方块的特定图案开发一种算法。
We're going to start with step one,
我们将从第一步开始，
doing an instance of the problem.
举一个问题实例。
And in this instance, I picked N equals three.
在本例中，我选择了 N 等于三。
So the first thing I'm going to do is work the problem by
因此，我要做的第一件事就是
hand without really thinking through exactly what I'm doing.
手工解决问题，而不必真正考虑自己在做什么。
That is, I'm going to do it right,
也就是说，我会做对的，
but I'm not going to try to write down what I did.
但我不会试图写下我的所作所为。
Once I've done that, I'm going to do step two where I
完成后，我将执行第二步，
write down exactly what I did in a step-by-step fashion.
逐步写下我所做的事情。
The first thing I did was put a blue square at zero, zero.
我做的第一件事是在零、零处放一个蓝色方块。
Then I put a red square at zero, one,
然后我把一个红色方块放在零，一个，
another red square at zero,
另一个红色方块放在零，
two, a blue square at zero,
二，一个蓝色方块放在零，
three, a red square at one,
三，一个红色方块放在一，一，
one, blue at one,
蓝色在一，
two, red at one, three,
二，红在一，三，红在二，二，二，
red at two, two, red at two,
红在二、三，红在二
three, and finally a blue at three, three.
、三，最后在三、三处放一个蓝色。
Now I'd like to generalize these steps,
现在我想概括一下这些步骤，
step three of the programming process.
即编程过程的第三步。
And if we look at the steps,
如果我们看一下这些步骤，
we can see there's some repetition and counting behavior,
我们可以看到有一些重复和计数行为，
which is going to help us generalize these steps into an algorithm.
这将有助于我们将这些步骤概括为算法。
These first four steps have x equals zero,
前四个步骤的 x 等于零，
then we have a group of three steps for x equals one,
然后我们有一组三个步骤表示 x 等于 1，
a group of two steps for x equals two,
一组两个步长表示 x 等于二，
and finally a single step for x equals three.
最后一个步长表示 x 等于三。
So we're repeating somewhat similar steps as we count x going from zero to three.
因此，我们在重复一些类似的步骤，因为我们计算x从零到三。
But exactly what we do varies.
但是我们到底做的事情各不相同。
We color the squares blue, red, red,
我们把方块涂成蓝色、红
blue for x equals zero or red, blue,
色、红色、蓝色代表x等于零或者红色、蓝色、
red for x equals one,
红色代表x等于一，
so the color pattern is something we still have to figure out.
所以颜色图案是我们仍然需要弄清楚的。
Also, how many steps in the y coordinate of each varies.
此外，每个 y 坐标中有多少步也各不相同。
Let's look at the y coordinates first,
让我们先看看 y 坐标，
coming back to the colors in a minute.
过一会儿再回到颜色上。
If we look at this first group of steps,
如果我们看一下第一组步骤，就会
we see that the y coordinates go from zero to three.
看到 y 坐标从零变为三。
If we look at the second group of steps,
如果我们看第二组步骤，
we see that the y coordinates go from one to three,
我们会看到 y 坐标从一到三
and in this third group, two to three.
，在第三组中，从二到三。
So it looks like, in general,
所以看来，总的来说，
we're counting from x to three.
我们正在从 x 数到 3。
If we ignore the colors for a moment,
如果我们暂时忽略颜色，
we can take this group of steps and say,
我们可以采取这一组步骤然后说，
we count from zero to three,
我们从零到三计数，
calling the number that we count y,
调出我们计数的数字 y，
then put a square of some color we'll figure out later at zero, y.
然后在零处放一个我们稍后会弄清楚的颜色的正方形，y。
And we can write similar steps for each of these other groups.
我们可以为其他每组写出类似的步骤。
And now we can use patterns in these steps to generalize our algorithm further.
现在我们可以在这些步骤中使用模式来进一步概括我们的算法。除了@@
Each set of steps is the same except for the x coordinate shown in bold,
以粗体显示的 x 坐标外，每组步骤都相同，
and these vary in a nice counting pattern.
而且这些步数各不相同，计数模式不错。
That is, we can say count from zero to three,
也就是说，我们可以说从零到三计数，
call each number that we count x,
调用我们计算的每个数字 x，
and for each of those numbers,
对于每个数字，
we'll count from x to three and call that y,
我们将从 x 计数到三然后称之为 y，然后在
and we'll put some color square at x, y.
x，y 处放一些彩色方块。
But this is only true for N equals three.
但这只对于 N 等于三才是正确的。
A clue that we have not finished generalizing
我们尚未完成概括的一个线索
is that the steps do not depend on N at all.
是，这些步骤根本不依赖于 N。
We know that the pattern will be different for different N,
我们知道不同的 N 的模式会有所不同，
but this is not reflected in the algorithm we wrote.
但这并未反映在我们编写的算法中。
We need to make it more general.
我们需要让它更笼统。
How could we do this?
我们怎么能做到这一点？
We might just realize it,
我们可能会意识到这一点，
but if we don't, we can go back and repeat steps one and two.
但如果我们没意识到，我们可以回过头来重复步骤一和二。
If the pattern is hard to figure out,
如果模式很难弄清楚，
we may have to do steps one and two many times.
我们可能需要多次执行第一步和第二步。
So for example, if we went back and performed step one for N equals one,
因此，举个例子，如果我们回过头来执行 N 等于一的步骤，
we end up with this pattern.
我们最终会得到这种模式。
And when we do step two,
当我们执行第二步时，
we write down these steps.
我们会写下这些步骤。
If we go through the generalization process again,
如果我们再次进行概括过程，
we see that we come up with these steps.
我们会看到我们想出了这些步骤。
Count from zero to one,
从零到一计数，
call it x; count from x to one, call it y;
称之为 x；从 x 计数为一，称之为 y；
then put a square of some color at x, y,
然后在 x，y 处放一个某种颜色的正方形，
which is very similar to N equals three except this number has changed.
这与 N 等于三非常相似，只是这个数字发生了变化。
For any N, we count from zero to N based on the pattern from our examples.
对于任何 N，我们根据示例中的模式从 0 到 N 进行计数。
Now we have a more generalized algorithm.
现在我们有了更通用的算法。
Of course, we need to figure out what the question marks are for the colors.
当然，我们需要弄清楚颜色的问号是什么。
To do that, we can go back to the colors from our N equals three example.
为此，我们可以回到我们的 N 等于三个示例中的颜色。
We had mostly red squares with some blue squares,
我们主要是红色方块和一些蓝色方块，
so we should figure out the pattern for when a square is blue.
所以我们应该弄清楚正方形何时为蓝色的图案。
I've thrown away the red ones so we can just look at blue for a pattern.
我把红色的丢掉了这样我们就可以用蓝色来寻找图案了。
This pattern may be a bit subtle to see with only four pieces of information.
只有四条信息，这种模式可能有点微妙。
You may have figured it out,
你可能已经弄清楚了，
but if not, what could you do?
但如果没有，你能做什么？
Well, it might be easier to see with more information.
好吧，如果有更多信息，可能会更容易看见。
Looking at N equals five,
看着 N 等于五，
we have more blue squares to consider.
我们还有更多的蓝色方块需要考虑。
Now, you look at the pattern and see what you come up with,
现在，你看看模式，看看你想出了什么，
and this is mostly your ability to look at numbers and find patterns.
这主要是你看数字和找到模式的能力。
If we add the x and y coordinates together,
如果我们将 x 和 y 坐标相加，
we see that they are zero, three,
就会发现它们是零、三、
three, six, six, six, and nine.
三、六、六、六、六和九。
So the pattern here, is we draw a blue square if
所以这里的模式是，当
and only if x plus y is a multiple of three.
且仅当 x 加 y 是三的倍数时，我们才画一个蓝色方块。
Now we can go back to our algorithm and specify if x plus y is a multiple of three,
现在我们可以回到我们的算法，指定 x 加 y 是否是三的倍数，
we put a blue square at x, y.
我们在 x, y 处放一个蓝色方块。
Otherwise, we put a red square at x, y.
否则，我们在 x, y 处放一个红方块。
This algorithm looks pretty good,
这个算法看起来不错，
but we will want to do step four and test it,
但我们要执行第四步并对其进行测试，
as shown in the next video.
如下一个视频所示。